mobymax.com 2019-01-25

# Privacy Policy | MobyMax

Privacy Policy

Last updated on February 21, 2018

Student privacy is just as important to us as it is to you.

Our security starts with the data you enter into our program. Only the most basic personal information (name and grade level) is entered into MobyMax.

We never share your information with third parties, with only one exception: with your explicit permission, we may allow educational researchers to access aggregate class information.

You can reach out to us. We’re here to answer any additional questions you might have. Please don’t hesitate to call us at 1-888-793-8331 (between 8 am and 5 pm ET) Monday-Friday, or email us at support@mobymax.com anytime.

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which MobyMax collects, uses, maintains and discloses personally identifiable information in records ("Student Records") collected from users ("User") of the www.MobyMax.com website ("Site"). This Privacy Policy applies to the Site and all the services offered by MobyMax on this Site. 

COPPA and FERPA

We are committed to working with our Users to comply with laws, rules, and regulations governing the use and protection of Student Records, including the Children Online Privacy Protection (COPPA) and the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and their implementing regulations, applicable state laws, and statues governing Student Records we receive from Users. As such, MobyMax is committed to protecting the security, confidentiality, and integrity of Student Records that we receive from Users, as well as to protecting against unauthorized access or anticipated threats. 

Personal identification information

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our Site, subscribe to email alerts, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, and phone number. Teachers or administrators choose which identifying information to include as the students' first name, last name, username, password, and ID. We never collect sensitive information such as student addresses, social security numbers, or dates of birth. We permit teachers

or administrators to replace student first and last names with nicknames or aliases. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site-related activities. Users can correct any erroneous personal information by emailing support@mobymax.com or calling (888)793-8331. 

Non-personal identification information

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users' means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

Web browser cookies

Our Site may use "cookies" to enhance Users' experience. A User's web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. Users may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert them when cookies are being sent, but this may result in some parts of the Site not functioning properly. 

How we use collected information

MobyMax may collect and use Users' personal information for improving the User’s experience or sending periodic emails. Students shall not receive email alerts containing any advertising or product information. We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site and so that we may improve our Site. If the User decides to opt-in to our email alerts, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. 

Property and control of student data

All student records and data continue to be the property of and under the control of the local educational agency. Students are able to access, print, and otherwise retain any student-generated content by accessing it through various channels in their student accounts. If teachers provide parents or guardians with login instructions, they are able to access basic student MobyMax data like progress, lessons completed, and time spent.

How we protect your information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices, and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information, and data stored on our Site. 

Sharing your personal information

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users' personal identification information to others. We will not allow unrelated third parties to use your personal information for any reason without your consent. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors, and users with our business partners for the purposes outlined above. We may disclose and share personal information with (1) our group companies or any entity which acquires any part of our business, (2) with our service providers (including, for example, suppliers who develop or host our sites), (3) with single sign-on providers that you use to access our software, (4) roster services that you use to update your student and teacher rosters, and (5) if required or permitted by law with other third parties with your consent.

Procedure for unauthorized records disclosure

In the event of a breach or unauthorized disclosure of student records that would be subject to disclosure under applicable federal or state law has occurred, MobyMax will take prompt and appropriate steps to mitigate further breach or release of student records, provide notice to the affected User promptly and without reasonable delay, and work with the affected User to provide information and assistance necessary to comply with any notification to parents, legal guardians, or students, as is required by applicable law. 

Contract termination/completion

Following expiration or termination of the agreement under which the User purchased access to the MobyMax web-based products or services, and upon receipt of written request from the User, MobyMax will destroy or, if agreed, return to the User, the Student Records in its possession within a commercially reasonable period of time. At any point, teachers or administrators are able to soft-delete or permanently delete student accounts and data. For clarity, data generated by MobyMax or our products that is in aggregate, or that is anonymized (i.e., personally identifiable information has been removed) may be retained by MobyMax and used for product improvement purposes. 

Changes to this privacy policy

We may update this Privacy Policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. If we change the policy in a material manner, for example, if we seek to use personal information in a materially different way than we had previously, we will provide at least 30 days’ notice to you so that you have sufficient time to evaluate the change in practice. Of course, you can always opt out by deleting your account before the changes take effect.

Your acceptance of these terms

Unless you have entered into your own school or district contract with MobyMax, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy by using this site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, please contact [support@mobymax.com](mailto:support@mobymax.com).
